<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<search>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>About Rongxin ZHU</title>
    <link href="/2025/02/20/Rongxin%20ZHU/"/>
    <url>/2025/02/20/Rongxin%20ZHU/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3 id="Rongxin-ZHU"><a href="#Rongxin-ZHU" class="headerlink" title="Rongxin ZHU"></a>Rongxin ZHU</h3><p><strong>Dr. Rongxin Zhu</strong> received his Ph.D. in Cyberspace Security in 2024. He is currently a lecturer at Hainan University,  and also an adjunct research fellow at Paradise Lab, University of Ottawa. Dr. Zhu was a visiting scholar at the University of Ottawa for one year. His research interests focus on the security of underwater sensor networks and the development of intelligent algorithms.</p><ul><li>📧 Email：rxzhu [at] ieee [dot] org</li><li>📄 <a href="https://scholar.google.com/citations?user=-GQiabMAAAAJ&hl=en">Google Scholar</a></li><li>🐙 <a href="https://github.com/">GitHub</a></li></ul><h3 id="Education"><a href="#Education" class="headerlink" title="Education"></a>Education</h3><ul><li><p><strong>Hainan University</strong>, Ph.D. in Cyberspace Security (2021.09 - 2024.06)  </p><ul><li>School of Software: Cyberspace Security</li></ul></li><li><p><strong>Nanjing University</strong>, M.E. in Software Engineering (2015.09 - 2017.06)  </p><ul><li>Institute of Software: Software Engineering</li></ul></li><li><p><strong>Nanjing Institute of Technology</strong>, B.S. in Computer Science (2011.09 - 2015.06)  </p><ul><li>School of Computer Science: Computer Science</li></ul></li></ul><h3 id="Publications"><a href="#Publications" class="headerlink" title="Publications"></a>Publications</h3><h4 id="Journal-Papers"><a href="#Journal-Papers" class="headerlink" title="Journal Papers"></a>Journal Papers</h4><ul><li>Chen, Y., <strong>Zhu, R.</strong>*, Boukerche, A., &amp; Yang, Q. (2025). AUV-Assisted data collection using hybrid clustering and reinforcement learning in underwater acoustic sensor networks. <em>Ad Hoc Networks</em>, 103877. (IF &#x3D; 4.8)</li><li><strong>Zhu, R.</strong>, et al. (2025). An Interference-aware and Collision-free MAC Protocol for Underwater Wireless Sensor Networks. <em>ACM Transactions on Sensor Networks</em>, 21(3), 1-26. (IF &#x3D; 3.9)</li><li><strong>Zhu, R.</strong>, Boukerche, A., Long, L., and Yang, Q. (2024). “Design Guidelines on Trust Management for Underwater Wireless Sensor Networks,” in <em>IEEE Communications Surveys &amp; Tutorials</em>, vol. 26, no. 4, pp. 2547-2576. (IF &#x3D; 35.6)</li><li><strong>Zhu, R.</strong>, Boukerche, A., Chen, Y., and Yang, Q. (2024). A reliable cluster-based opportunistic routing protocol for underwater wireless sensor networks. <em>Computer Networks</em>, 251, 110622. (IF &#x3D; 5.6)</li><li><strong>Zhu, R.</strong>, Boukerche, A., and Yang, Q. (2024). An Efficient Secure and Adaptive Routing Protocol Based on GMM-HMM-LSTM for Internet of Underwater Things. <em>IEEE Internet of Things Journal</em>, vol. 11, no. 9, pp. 16491-16504. (IF &#x3D; 10.6)</li><li><strong>Zhu, R.</strong>, Boukerche, A., Li, D., and Yang, Q. (2024). Delay-aware and reliable medium access control protocols for UWSNs: Features, protocols, and classification. <em>Computer Networks</em>, 110631. (IF &#x3D; 5.6)</li><li><strong>Zhu, R.</strong>, Boukerche, A., Huang, X., and Yang, Q. (2023). DESLR: Energy-efficient and secure layered routing based on channel-aware trust model for UASNs. <em>Computer Networks</em>, 109939. (IF &#x3D; 5.6)</li><li><strong>Zhu, R.</strong>, Boukerche, A., Feng, L., and Yang, Q. (2023). A trust management-based secure routing protocol with AUV-aided path repairing for Underwater Acoustic Sensor Networks. <em>Ad Hoc Networks</em>, 103212. (IF &#x3D; 4.8)</li><li><strong>Zhu, R.</strong>, et al. (2024). DC-MAC: A Delay-aware and Collision-free MAC Protocol Based on Game Theory for Underwater Wireless Sensor Networks. <em>IEEE Sensors Journal</em>, 24(5), 6930-6941. (IF &#x3D; 4.3)</li><li><strong>Zhu, R.</strong>, Jiang, Q., Huang, X., Li, D., and Yang, Q. (2022). A reinforcement-learning-based opportunistic routing protocol for energy-efficient and Void-Avoided UASNs. <em>IEEE Sensors Journal</em>, 22(13), 13589-13601. (IF &#x3D; 4.3)</li><li><strong>Zhu, R.</strong>, Huang, X., Huang, X., Li, D., and Yang, Q. (2022). An On-Site-Based Opportunistic Routing Protocol for Scalable and Energy-Efficient Underwater Acoustic Sensor Networks. <em>Applied Sciences</em>, 12(23), 12482. (IF &#x3D; 2.7)</li><li><strong>Zhu, R.</strong>, et al. Value Iteration Solving Algorithm for POMDP Based on Optimizing Environmental State Distribution. <em>Application Research of Computers</em>, 2022, 39(02):374-378. (Chinese Journal)</li><li>Chen, Y., Li, Z., and <strong>Zhu, R.</strong>*. (2024). “A Blockchain-Based Edge Computing Group Signature Authentication Model for Underwater Clustered Networks,” <em>Journal of Marine Science and Engineering</em>, vol. 13, no. 1, p. 27. (IF &#x3D; 2.8)</li><li>Xue, L., Lei, H.*, and <strong>Zhu, R.</strong>*. (2025). “A collision avoidance MAC protocol with power control for adaptive clustering underwater sensor networks,” <em>Journal of Marine Science and Engineering</em>, vol. 13, no. 1, p. 76. (IF &#x3D; 2.8)</li></ul><h4 id="Conference-Papers"><a href="#Conference-Papers" class="headerlink" title="Conference Papers"></a>Conference Papers</h4><ul><li>Zhu, R., et al. (2024, December). Enhancing Source Location Privacy in UASNs: A Multi-Armed Bandit and Pseudopacket Scheduling Approach. In GLOBECOM 2024-2024 IEEE Global Communications Conference (pp. 1053-1058). IEEE.</li><li>Zhu, R., Boukerche, A., Li, P., and Yang, Q. (2024, June). A Traffic-Aware Trust Model Based on Edge Computing for Underwater Wireless Sensor Networks. In ICC 2024-IEEE International Conference on Communications (pp. 2390-2395). IEEE. (Best Paper)</li><li>Zhu, R., Boukerche, A., Huang, X., and Yang, Q. (2023). GHL-SAR: Secure and Adaptive Routing Based on GMM-HMM-LSTM for UASNs. IEEE Globecom 2023, Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia, pp. 4540-4545. </li><li>Jiang, Q., Zhu, R., Boukerche, A., &amp; Yang, Q. (2024, April). An AUV-Assisted Data Collection Approach for UASNs Based on Hybrid Clustering and Matrix Completion. In 2024 IEEE Wireless Communications and Networking Conference (WCNC) (pp. 1-6). IEEE.</li><li>Zhu, R., Boukerche, A., and Yang, Q. (2023). Towards a Trusted Channel Energy-Aware Routing Algorithm for Underwater Sensor Networks. Q2SWinet’23, New York, NY, USA: Association for Computing Machinery, Oct. 2023, pp. 1–6. doi: 10.1145&#x2F;3616391.3622777.</li><li>Boukerche, A., Zhu, R., and Yang, Q. (2023). T-SAPR: An Efficient Q-Learning Trust-based Secure Routing Protocol for Underwater Acoustic Sensor Networks. Q2SWinet’23, New York, NY, USA: Association for Computing Machinery, Oct. 2023, pp. 1–6. doi: 10.1145&#x2F;3616391.3622776.</li></ul><h3 id="Course"><a href="#Course" class="headerlink" title="Course"></a>Course</h3><ul><li>Python Programming</li><li>Data Structure and Programming</li><li>Research Methodology(Graduate)</li></ul><h3 id="ACADEMIC-SERVICES"><a href="#ACADEMIC-SERVICES" class="headerlink" title="ACADEMIC SERVICES"></a>ACADEMIC SERVICES</h3><h4 id="GUEST-EDITOR"><a href="#GUEST-EDITOR" class="headerlink" title="GUEST EDITOR"></a>GUEST EDITOR</h4><ul><li><em>Photonics</em>, Special Issue on <a href="https://www.mdpi.com/journal/photonics/special_issues/V9D09W10J9">Applications and Development of Optical Fiber Sensors</a>, February 2025</li></ul><h4 id="Youth-AE"><a href="#Youth-AE" class="headerlink" title="Youth AE"></a>Youth AE</h4><ul><li><em>Exploration</em>, since April 2025</li></ul><h4 id="Journal-Reviewer"><a href="#Journal-Reviewer" class="headerlink" title="Journal Reviewer"></a>Journal Reviewer</h4><ul><li>Infocom 2024-Present</li><li>IEEE Internet of Things Journal,2023 – Present</li><li>IEEE Transactions on Mobile Computing, 2022 – Present</li><li>IEEE Sensors Journal, 2022 – Present</li><li>Computer Networks, 2022 – 2023</li><li>Artificial Intelligence Review, 2023 – 2024</li><li>Cluster Computing, 2024 – Present</li><li>IEEE Network, 2024 – Present</li><li>Wireless Personal Communications, 2024 – Present</li></ul>]]></content>
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  
</search>
